# **Shreyas Ramnath**

Email: ramnathshreyas@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/shreyasramnath | Phone: (321)-616-2583

## **SUMMARY**

Skilled Software Engineer with experience creating dynamic web applications. Team-oriented and coachable professional with the ability to implement and manage SQL and NoSQL database operations and data structures. Good grasp of Restful Web Services, JSON & GraphQL, and Service-Oriented Architecture.

# **EDUCATION**

Florida Institute of Technology, 3.5
MS Computer Science
BMS Institute of Technology & Management, 3.0
Bachelor's in information science & Engineering

Aug 2016 – Jul 2018 Melbourne, FL Aug 2011–Jun 2015 Bengaluru, India

### **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES5/ES6), Typescript, Java

Web and Other Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Bootstrap, AdobeXD, Invision, React.js, Node.js, Next.js, Express.js, GraphQL, URQL, Apollo, Spring, JPA

Database and Cloud: PostgreSQL, MySQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Jenkins, SonarQube, Linux CLI, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS

Source Control: Git, GitHub, Bit bucket, Jira, Confluence, Swagger2.0

Certifications: AWS Developer Associate, AWS Solutions Architect Associate, Oracle Java Associate

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Idexcel, Herndon VA - Full Stack Engineer

Jul 2019 - present

- Working on a Loan Origination & Commercial Lending Software aiding banks for Individual, Commercial, and Real Estate loan processing, part of three module development: Financial Analyzer, Underwriting, and Back Office.
- Fashioned a Spreadsheet tool using TypeScript & React.js which was responsive and interactive and built a pdf print and export functionality for PEMDAS-based account calculations for a loan entity. Used Hooks and ContextAPI state management.
- Worked on designing the wireframes, mockups, and icons using AdobeXD and Invision based on user stories and product team requirements.
- Implemented memoization to make state transitions more efficient in terms of re-rendering and copying using Immutable.js along with React.
- Involved in writing the CSS using SASS. Used partials, mixins, and functions to make the CSS files more functional and compact.
- Wrote polyfills to handle cross-browser compatibility issues in IE 7, 8, 9, and FF. Used Lighthouse.js for representing data visualizations.
- Developed the product support and customer help page using Next.js and server-side rendering for better performance.
- Designed microservices based on REST using Node.js, Express.js, and PostgreSQL database running on AWS-RDS service.
- Developed **Serverless Rest APIs** using **Node.js, AWS Lambda, and API Gateway** for loan approval workflow, and constructed File Manager APIs to upload loan documents using several **AWS** services. Used **step functions** to orchestrate the state machines for the approval workflow.
- Used Elastic Kubernetes Service to manage the deployment and scaling of the independently dockerized front-end and backend applications.
- Worked with Jest, Enzyme, react-testing library to write unit tests for the pages and common components of the front-end application.
- Constructed unit test cases and mock scenarios using Mocha, Chai, and Cypress.io, followed the test-driven development (TDD) process.
- Configured CodeDeploy, CodePipeline for the CI/CD process wrote CF templates, set up the SonarQube service to perform static code analysis.
- Followed 12-factor methodology for building our product as a software-as-a-service (SaaS) offering our financial clients and mid-tier banks.
- Involved in entire SDLC, follow SAFe Agile working on groomed user stories, daily scrums, and regular peer code reviews and sprint demos.

#### Vamana Systems, Alpharetta GA – Full Stack Engineer

Oct 2018 - July 2019

- Built an NLP chatbot application as our client-facing product using Typescript, React, and Node.js, Express.js stack with a DynamoDB database.
- Design, develop and test HTML5, CSS3, LESS which met accessibility (a11y) and web browser standards for our website.
- Added optimization techniques to reduce the page size and load times to enhance user experience using sprites.
- Built stable **React components** and stand-alone functions to be added to any future pages. Used **React-Router** to navigate to different pages.
- Maintained global states in the stores and dispatched the actions and created multiple reducers to perform state changes using Redux.
- Used middleware, redux-thunk in application to retrieve data from the backend, and to also perform Restful services.
- Worked with **Jest** to write unit tests for the pages and common components. Configured **code-splitting** with **Webpack** to improve performance.
- Developed backend REST services using Node.js, Express.js, along with DynamoDB as the backend NoSQL database.
- Wrote unit test cases, mock scenarios wrote browser-based regression automation suites using Mocha, Chai, and Cypress.io.
- The application was containerized using **Docker** and used **Cloud Formation** templates to deploy our application to **AWS**.
- Built a search engine application for an efficient and flexible searchable scheme in the cloud, using Elastic Search.
- Developed the front-end using TypeScript and React.js and backend using Java, Spring Boot, JPA, and a SQL-based MySQL database.
- Wrote the schema, stored procedures, and functions **SQL** database. Configured the **Jenkins** server for continuous integration and continuous deployment process. Also developed the **DDL** and **DML**, **SQL-based** scripts to query the database for transaction data during quarterly audits.
- Wrote smoke, functional test scenarios along with unit test cases for the reusable component library and the individual pages in the application.
- Followed Agile XP methodology with weekly release cycles and constant communication with scrum masters and business owners.